<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This is an automatically generated file. -->
<Chapter Label="Chapter_Drawing_the_Faithful_Transitive_Permutation_Representation_Graph">
<Heading>Drawing the Faithful Transitive Permutation Representation Graph</Heading>

<Section Label="Chapter_Drawing_the_Faithful_Transitive_Permutation_Representation_Graph_Section_Drawing_functions">
<Heading>Drawing functions</Heading>

<P/>
 One of the advantages of Faithful Transitive Permutation Representation Graph are on Groups generated by involutions, such as C-groups.
 These graphs are very useful in the research of abstract polytopes and hypertopes, mainly called as "Schreier coset graphs" or "CPR graphs" in this area. 
 Here we will give a function that builds this graph given a permutation group generated by involutions, a group and one of its core-free subgroups or by giving an isomorphism of the group into the symmetric group acting faithfully and transitively on its domain.
 To use Graphviz in order to create the image file, you need to be running GAP on a Linux Environment (Windows Subsystem for Linux is supported), with graphviz installed.
<P/>
<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="H, K, filename [, layout, filetype]" Name="DotFTPRGraph" Label="for IsPermGroup"/>
 <Returns>exports both a .dot file and an image file
</Returns>
 <Description>
 Given a transitive permutation group <A>G</A>, a faithful transitive permutation representation of a group <A>map</A> or a group <A>H</A> and one of its core-free subgroups <A>K</A>, the function will write a .dot file in the current path where GAP is running. 
 If Graphviz is installed, the function will also create an image file on the current path.
 If neither layout nor the filetype is specified, then the default layout is "neato" and the filetype is "svg".
 The layouts can be one of the following: ["dot", "neato", "twopi", "circo", "fdp", "sfdp", "patchwork", "osage"] while the
 filetypes can be one of the following: ["dot", "xdot", "ps", "pdf", "svg", "svgz", "png", "gif", "jpg", "jpeg", "json", "imap", "cmapx"].
<Example><![CDATA[

]]></Example>


 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="arg1,arg2,arg3" Name="DrawImageFTPRGraph" Label="for IsPermGroup,IsString,IsString"/>
 <Description>
<P/>
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="arg1,arg2" Name="TeXFTPRGraph" Label="for IsPermGroup,IsString"/>
 <Description>
<P/>
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="arg1,arg2" Name="DrawTeXFTPRGraph" Label="for IsPermGroup,IsString"/>
 <Description>
<P/>
 </Description>
</ManSection>


</Section>


</Chapter>

